

Junaitha Begum A. M

9043720227; junaithabegumam@gmail.com Coimbatore, India.

Career Summary

Professional Chef with experience in multi cuisine 20+ years of North Indian, South Indian, Indo-Chinese, International / Continental, Arabian/Lebanese Cuisines, Seas Foods, Traditional Sweets, Pastry, Specialized in Biryani, Parotta. Capable of managing dining services from 200 to 1000 members i.e 25kg to 100kg in quantity while supervising and motivating staff to perform the best of their abilities across every service. Thorough understanding of HACCP procedures. Excellent understanding of recipe modification and nutrient composition along with advanced nutrition skills aimed at preparing specialized food items, menu planning, tracking inventory, controlling costs etc.

Education

Paark Institute of Hotel Management and Catering Technology - *Bachelor in Hotel Management*

Paark Institute of Hotel Management and Catering Technology - *Diploma in Food & Beverage Production*

AnnaMalai University , Chidambaram - B. A Sociology

Skills

- North Indian cuisine (Bengali, Punjabi, Kashimiri, Lucknowi, Mughalai, Goan, Bohra)
- South Indian cuisine (Chettinad, Malabar, Andhra, Mangalorean, Udupi)

- Indo-Chinese / Asian Cuisine
- Specialized in Seafoods (Lobster, Squid, Crab, Shellfish, Sushi, Oyster, Shrimp, Mussels)
- Arabian / Lebanese Cuisine (Middle eastern)(Shawarma 20+varieties, Kuzhi
 Mandi, Kabsa, Alfahm, Majbous, Madhooth, Shawaya, Bukhari rice, Falafel, Malawah)
- International /Continental cuisine(Pizza, Burger, Sandwich, Spaghetti, Carbonara, Lasagna, Pasta, Casserole, Tacos, Nachos, Enchiladas, Burritos, Fajitas, Croissant)
- Cordon Bleu
- Well-tuned Palette, Seasonal Cooking trends
- Pastry, Baking, Traditional Sweets, BBQ, Grill, Tandoor, Food Science
- Leadership, Adaptability, Knife Skills, Collaboration

Experience

Jan 2018 - PRESENT

Vijay Elanza 4 Star , Saibaba colony - Chef de cuisine

Key Contribution

- Managing daily kitchen operations with staff members of 20.
- Collaborating with others Chef for menu redesign while being the head of process and implementing new courses according to guest obligations.
- Overseas food production and preparation, ensuring food safety procedures are 100% adhered to.
- Accountable for responsibilities of department heads and took ownership of all guest complaints.
- Delegating as appropriate to develop supervisors and subordinates to accept responsibility and meet clearly defined goals and objectives.
- Consistently delivered new innovative recipes for exceeding guest expectations.
- Handling the expenses on Food & beverages and the ability to react with impactful strategies according to Profit & Loss statements.
- Acting as one of the members in the final decision maker of hiring key staff.
- Dedicating time to develop the kitchen team using our developmental framework.
- Building and managing menus to cater to diverse needs across different cuisines.
- Accurately co-ordinated accident records in turn ensuring all hazards are reviewed to minimize the rise of future incidents.

Dec 2010 - Dec 2017

Metro Bukit Bintang 3 Star, Kuala Lumpur -Sous Chef

Key Contribution

- Developed food processes that increased the economy by 40% simultaneously improved the monthly & yearly turnover to 70%.
- Trained and directed all Chef De Partie since 2010 to meet and exceed established food preparation standards on a consistent basis, improving kitchen operation flow by 50%, while maintaining 100% employee abilities.

- Display exceptional leadership by providing a positive work environment, counselling employees as appropriate and demonstrating a dedicated and professional approach to management.
- Redeveloped menu, managed relationships with vendors, negotiating prices of ingredients and equipment that resulted in a 10% savings on budget.
- Identifies the developmental needs of kitchen staff and provides coaching, mentoring, and also helping them to improve their knowledge or skills.
- Prepared meals for lunch and dining services with an average of 200 persons per day
- Monitored and recorded inventory, and ordered new supplies when necessary.
- Analyzed recipes to assign prices to menu items, based on food, labor, and overhead costs.

Dec 2006 - Oct 2010

Holiday Inn Singapore Orchard City Centre 4 Star - Senior & Pastry Chef De Partie

- Prepare and Create complicated dishes such as Soufflés and Gourmet soups.
- Followed directions and maintained good working relationships with Managers and Supervisors.
- Overseas and executed pastry productions for buffets and banquets.
- Reviews GSTS and RSTS comment cards for guest satisfaction results and other data to identify areas of improvement.
- Researched and Developed pastry recipes to keep with the trend and Hospitality standards.
- Determines how food should be presented, and creates decorative food displays.
- Actively coordinated in new Hospitality & Events brochures in line with seasonal trends and changes
- Assisted Sou Chef in training and developing Commis, Second cooks and new Staff's setting them
 up for success.
- Involved in providing feedback with performance management of associates to Sous Chef.
- Associated in adapting to seasonality of products and cooking trends.

Oct 2002 - Nov 2006

Sangam 3 Star, Thanjavur - Chef de partie

Key Contribution

- Responsible for cuisines courses and making sound decisions to help the management achieve its projected sales.
- Maintained a farm-to-fork kitchen direction.
- Inspecting the quality of food preparation by commi while actively performing assigned duties.
- Mentored and trained four Commis, improving their performance by 20%.

Feb 2000 - Sep 2002

Temple Tower, Thanjavur - Commis Chef

Key Contribution

- Prepared all food items in a 50 seat South Indian Cuisine restaurant from Breakfast, Lunch to Dinner services, assisting restaurants with maintaining their high standards throughout the year.
- Actively trained under CDP, Sous Chef and performed the recipes as per the guidance from Senior Staff.

Certifications

Certified in Culinary Arts (CCA) 2010

The Associate of Occupational Studies (AOS) in Culinary Arts. 2013

Certified in Gastronomy (CG) 2015

Others

Gender Female

(Signature)

Junaitha Begum